Guide to the John Franklin Enders Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Correspondence and Topical Files, 1916-1988; Series I; 36.75' (88 boxes)
  - Spink, Wesley W., 1936, 1960-1961 (Box 82, Folder 1836)
  - Spooner, E. T. C., 1950-1951, 1954, 1961 (Box 82, Folder 1837)
  - Sprague, Howard, 1956 (Box 82, Folder 1838)
  - Sprecher, S., 1970 (Box 82, Folder 1839)
  - Springer-Verlag, 1971-1972 (Box 82, Folder 1840)
  - Squibb Institute for Medical Research, 1939-1940, 1947, 1950 (Box 82, Folder 1841)
  - Stähelin, Hartmann, 1955 (Box 82, Folder 1842)
  - Stafseth, H. J., 1940 (Box 82, Folder 1843)
  - Stalder, Johann, 1971-1974, 1977, undated (Box 82, Folder 1844)
  - Stalker, Hugh, 1940 (Box 82, Folder 1845)
  - Stanford University Hospital, 1957 (Box 82, Folder 1846)
  - Stanley, N. F., 1960-1961 (Box 82, Folder 1847)
  - Stanley, Wendell M., 1951-1952, 1956-1964, undated (Box 82, Folder 1848)
  - Stare, Fredrick J., 1957 (Box 82, Folder 1849)
  - Stark, John E., 1967 (Box 82, Folder 1850)
  - Stark, Marvin M., 1953-1955, 1958-1959 (Box 82, Folder 1851)
  - Steeves, Richard A., 1971 (Box 82, Folder 1852)
  - Steigman, Alex J., 1951-1954, 1957, 1960, 1963-1970, 1973-1974 (Box 82, Folder 1853)
  - Sterling-Winthrop Research Institute, 1953, 1960-1963 (Box 82, Folder 1854)
  - Stern, Gustav, 1958, 1961, 1967-1969, undated (Box 82, Folder 1855)
  - Stewart, Sarah E., 1959 (Box 82, Folder 1856)
  - Stoddard, Mrs. Charles, 1971 (Box 82, Folder 1857)
  - Stoker, M. G. P., 1951-1952, 1958, 1961-1966, undated (Box 82, Folder 1858)
  - Stokes, Joseph, 1948, 1958-1962, 1965-1968, 1971, undated (Box 82, Folder 1859)
  - Strauss, Lewis L., 1968 (Box 82, Folder 1860)
  - Stroder, J., 1951-1963 (Box 83, Folder 1861)
  - Stuart-Harris, C. H., 1953-1954, 1957, 1961-1962, 1965-1966 (Box 83, Folder 1862)
  - Stulberg, Cyril, 1956 (Box 83, Folder 1863)
  - Suffolk University, 1962 (Box 83, Folder 1864)
  - Sulkin, S. Edward, 1948 (Box 83, Folder 1865)
  - Sullivan, Julia C., 1946, 1955, 1958, 1967-1972, undated (Box 83, Folder 1866)
  - Sunday Mirror Magazine, 1946 (Box 83, Folder 1867)
  - Suzuki, Shigemi, 1958, 1964, undated (Box 83, Folder 1868)
    See also: box 38, folder 898
  - Svedmyr, Arne, 1950-1952 (Box 83, Folder 1869)
    See also: box 45, folder 1117-1118
  - Svedmyr, Arne, 1953-1958, 1964-1965, 1970-1971, 1980 (Box 83, Folder 1870)
  - Swachman, Harry, 1948-1954 (Box 83, Folder 1871)
  - Swartz, Morton, 1972 (Box 83, Folder 1872)
  - Sycamore, Thomas A. H., 1957-1959 (Box 83, Folder 1873)
  - Symmers, W. St. C., 1951 (Box 83, Folder 1874)
  - Syverton, Jerome, 1949-1951, 1955-1961 (Box 83, Folder 1875)
    See also: box 62, folders 1413-1420 See also: box 63, folders 1421-1424
  - Takemori, N., 1952-1955 (Box 83, Folder 1876)
  - Tamm, Igor, 1964 (Box 83, Folder 1877)
  - Taneja, Dr., 1958 (Box 83, Folder 1878)
  - Tatlock, Hugh, 1943 (Box 83, Folder 1879)
  - Tauraso, Nicola, 1957-1959, 1970-1972 (Box 83, Folder 1880)
  - Tavern Club, 1938, 1976 (Box 83, Folder 1881)
  - Taylor, John W., 1944 (Box 83, Folder 1882)
  - Taylor, R. M., 1949 (Box 83, Folder 1883)
  - Tegtmeyer, Peter, 1966-1974, undated (Box 83, Folder 1884)
  - Tenney, Benjamin, 1961 (Box 83, Folder 1885)
  - Tersin, Alexander, 1953-1956, 1959-1962, 1967 (Box 83, Folder 1886)
  - Tevethia, S. E., 1972 (Box 83, Folder 1887)
  - Tezek, O. Fethi, 1951 (Box 83, Folder 1888)
  - Theiler, Max, 1942 (Box 83, Folder 1889)
  - Thiry, Simon G., 1957, 1961 (Box 83, Folder 1890)
  - Thomas, Lewis, 1942-1943 (Box 83, Folder 1891)
  - Thompson, Randall, 1954-1955, 1958-1961, undated (Box 83, Folder 1892)
    See also: box 45, folder 1137 See also: box 82, folder 1854 See also: box 85, folder 1962
  - Thorn, George, 1943-1945 (Box 83, Folder 1893)
  - Thorndike, Augustus, 1956-1957 (Box 83, Folder 1894)
  - Thorndike, Rose, 1941, 1945 (Box 83, Folder 1895)
  - Thorpe, Edward S., 1946, 1949 (Box 83, Folder 1896)
  - Thursday Evening Club of Boston, 1946, 1955, 1972, undated (Box 83, Folder 1897)
  - Time, 1952-1954, 1960-1964 (Box 83, Folder 1898)
  - Tissue Culture Advisory Committee, 1952, 1959, 1969-1970, undated (Box 83, Folder 1899)
  - Tissue Culture Association, 1955-1958 (Box 83, Folder 1900)
  - Tissue culture notes, 1949, undated (Box 84, Folder 1901)
  - Tissue Culture Symposium, 1953-1954 (Box 84, Folder 1902)
  - Tobey, Harold G., 1948-1949 (Box 84, Folder 1903)
  - Todaro, George J., 1965 (Box 84, Folder 1904)
  - Todorov, Svetoslav, 1958 (Box 84, Folder 1905)
  - Toland, Owen J., 1944 (Box 84, Folder 1906)
  - Toolan, Helene W., 1965-1970 (Box 84, Folder 1907)
  - Toomey, Edward G., 1975 (Box 84, Folder 1908)
  - Topping, Norman, 1945 (Box 84, Folder 1909)
  - Torres, Sylvio T., 1956 (Box 84, Folder 1910)
  - Traggis, D. M., 1955 (Box 84, Folder 1911)
  - Treffers, Henry P., 1950 (Box 84, Folder 1912)
  - Trinity College, 1955-1956, 1962, 1965 (Box 84, Folder 1913)
  - Trombetta, N., 1962 (Box 84, Folder 1914)
  - Tucker, Charles A., 1942 (Box 84, Folder 1915)
  - Tufts University, 1960 (Box 84, Folder 1916)
  - Tulane University, 1955, 1958 (Box 84, Folder 1917)
  - Tullis, James L., 1951-1952, 1963 (Box 84, Folder 1918)
  - Tyler, Richard, 1970 (Box 84, Folder 1919)
  - Tyrell, David, 1954-1957 (Box 84, Folder 1920)
  - Tyzzer, Ernest, 1941, 1965-1966 (Box 84, Folder 1921)
  - Ubell, Earl, 1956 (Box 84, Folder 1922)
  - Ueda, Takeo, 1958 (Box 84, Folder 1923)
  - Union of Concerned Scientists, 1977 (Box 84, Folder 1924)
  - United Cerebral Palsy Annual Luncheon, 1957 (Box 84, Folder 1925)
  - United Nations Association, 1984 (Box 84, Folder 1926)
  - United Press International, 1962 (Box 84, Folder 1927)
  - United States Army Biological Laboratories, 1960-1963 (Box 84, Folder 1928)
  - Université de Toulouse. Académie des Sciences, 1970-1971 (Box 84, Folder 1929)
  - University of Chicago: Howard Taylor Ricketts Award, 1962, 1970-1973 (Box 84, Folder 1930)
  - University of Connecticut, 1963-1964, 1967 (Box 84, Folder 1931)
  - University of Hartford, 1960-1965, undated (Box 84, Folder 1932)
  - University of Ibadan, 1967-1968 (Box 84, Folder 1933)
  - University of Illinois. College of Medicine, 1949 (Box 84, Folder 1934)
  - University of London, 1961 (Box 84, Folder 1935)
  - University of Maryland, 1958-1959 (Box 84, Folder 1936)
  - University of Massachusetts at Amherst, 1955, 1963-1964 (Box 84, Folder 1937)
  - University of Michigan, 1955, 1959 (Box 84, Folder 1938)
  - University of Michigan Press, 1959-1960 (Box 84, Folder 1939)
  - University of Nebraska. College of Medicine, 1962 (Box 84, Folder 1940)
  - University of Southern California, 1945, 1956 (Box 84, Folder 1941)
  - University of Washington, 1964 (Box 84, Folder 1942)
  - University of Wisconsin, 1964 (Box 84, Folder 1943)
  - Upjohn Company, 1949, 1954-1957 (Box 84, Folder 1944)
  - Upper Volta award: measles, 1965, undated (Box 84, Folder 1945)
  - Uzman, Betty, 1967-1970, 1976 (Box 84, Folder 1946)
  - Vaccinia: Aronson, Philip R. and others, 1948, 1956-1958 (Box 84, Folder 1947)
  - van der Noordaa, Jan, 1964-1969, 1972-1976, undated (Box 84, Folder 1948)
  - van Rooyen, C. E., 1961-1963 (Box 84, Folder 1949)
  - Varicella, 1961 (Box 84, Folder 1950)
  - Varicella data, 1975-1976 (Box 84, Folder 1951)
  - Vaughan, Henry F., 1940 (Box 84, Folder 1952)
  - Veldee, M. V., 1943, 1956-1957 (Box 84, Folder 1953)
  - Velluci, Alfred E., 1976 (Box 85, Folder 1954)
  - Vesenjak, Jelka, 1954 (Box 85, Folder 1955)
  - Vietnam moratorium, 1969 (Box 85, Folder 1956)
  - Viets, Henry R., 1962 (Box 85, Folder 1957)
  - Vieuchange, Jean, 1947-1951, 1955-1958 (Box 85, Folder 1958)
  - Vieuchange, Jean, 1961-1967, 1971, undated (Box 85, Folder 1959)
  - Villee, Claude A., 1970 (Box 85, Folder 1960)
  - Viral and Rickettsial Diseases of Man: revision of book, 1951 (Box 85, Folder 1961)
  - Viral and Rickettsial Registry, 1965-1971 (Box 85, Folder 1962)
    See also: box 83, folder 1892
  - "Viral Infections of the Central Nervous System", 1959 (Box 85, Folder 1963)
  - Virology, 1954-1962, 1965-1968, undated (Box 85, Folder 1964)
  - Virology Dinner Group, 1971-1972, undated (Box 85, Folder 1965)
  - Viruses in Search of Disease: conference
    - Coxsackie session, 1956, undated (Box 85, Folder 1966)
    - ECHO virus session, 1955-1956, undated (Box 85, Folder 1967)
  - Viruses in tumors: miscellaneous correspondence, 1962 (Box 85, Folder 1968)
  - Visitors, 1941, 1945-1959 (Box 85, Folder 1969-1978)
  - Visitors, 1960-1970, undated (Box 86, Folder 1979-1985)
  - Visitors to Enders's laboratory, list of, 1949-1976 (Box 86, Folder 1986)
  - Vogt, Peter K., 1965, 1971 (Box 86, Folder 1987)
  - Vogue, 1955-1956 (Box 86, Folder 1988)
  - Vollmer, C., 1941 (Box 86, Folder 1989)
  - Vollmer, Herman, 1955 (Box 86, Folder 1990)
  - Volpe, John A., 1967 (Box 86, Folder 1991)
  - von Magnus, Herdis, 1951, 1955 (Box 86, Folder 1992)
  - von Magnus, Preben, 1957-1959 (Box 86, Folder 1993)
  - von Meralt, A., 1954 (Box 86, Folder 1994)
  - Voroshilova, Marina
    See: box 16, folders 331-332
  - Wahl, Manfred, 1955 (Box 86, Folder 1995)
  - Waksman, Byron H., 1960-1961, 1971 (Box 86, Folder 1996)
  - Waksman, Selman A., 1942 (Box 86, Folder 1997)
  - Wallace Laboratories, 1955 (Box 86, Folder 1998)
  - Wallbank, Alfred M., 1975 (Box 86, Folder 1999)
  - Walter Reed Army Institute of Research: Global Medicine course, 1963 (Box 86, Folder 2000)
  - Ward, Hugh, 1940, 1944-1951, 1956-1963, 1968, 1971-1972, undated (Box 86, Folder 2001)
  - Ward, John, 1958-1959 (Box 86, Folder 2002)
  - Ward, Robert, 1946-1953, 1957-1958, 1970-1971, undated (Box 86, Folder 2003)
    See also: box 4, folders 80-81
  - Warren, Joel, 1968 (Box 86, Folder 2004)
  - Warren, Robert T., 1963-1967, undated (Box 86, Folder 2005)
  - Warts, 1965 (Box 86, Folder 2006)
  - Watkins, Edward, 1958 (Box 86, Folder 2007)
  - Watson, Barbara K., 1964, 1968-1969 (Box 86, Folder 2008)
  - Weaver, Harry M., 1965-1967, undated (Box 86, Folder 2009)
  - Weech, A. Ashley, 1958-1963 (Box 86, Folder 2010)
  - Weeks, Edward, 1959, 1964-1967, 1973 (Box 86, Folder 2011)
  - Wehrle, Paul F., 1964 (Box 86, Folder 2012)
  - Weil, Roger, 1964-1966, 1970 (Box 86, Folder 2013)
  - Weinberger, Caspar W., 1973 (Box 86, Folder 2014)
  - Weizman Institute of Science, 1963-1964, 1969-1971, undated (Box 86, Folder 2015)
  - Welch, Barbara Anne, 1959 (Box 86, Folder 2016)
  - Wellcome Research Laboratories, 1954, 1960 (Box 86, Folder 2017)
  - Weller, Thomas H., 1952-1953, 1956 (Box 86, Folder 2018)
  - Wenner, Herbert A., 1948-1957, 1961-1962, 1965-1966, undated (Box 87, Folder 2019)
  - Werthessen, N. T., 1951-1953, 1961 (Box 87, Folder 2020)
  - Wesslen, Tore, 1961, 1968-1970 (Box 87, Folder 2021)
  - Western Reserve University, 1958 (Box 87, Folder 2022)
  - Westwood, J., 1955 (Box 87, Folder 2023)
  - WGBH: Lowell, Ralph, 1959-1960, undated (Box 87, Folder 2024)
  - White, Paul Dudley, 1965 (Box 87, Folder 2025)
  - Who's Who, 1961, 1971, undated (Box 87, Folder 2026)
  - Who's Who in America, 1958 (Box 87, Folder 2027)
  - Wildly, Peter, 1961, undated (Box 87, Folder 2028)
  - Wilfert, Catherine M., 1965-1971, undated (Box 87, Folder 2029-2030)
  - Williams, Greer, 1958-1960, 1967-1969 (Box 87, Folder 2031)
  - Williams and Wilkins Company, 1957 (Box 87, Folder 2032)
  - Wilson, Edwin B., 1940, 1949, 1964 (Box 87, Folder 2033)
  - Wilson, James L., 1957-1958 (Box 87, Folder 2034)
  - Winsser, J., 1947-1948 (Box 87, Folder 2035)
  - Winter, P. G., 1957 (Box 87, Folder 2036)
  - Wislocki Memorial Fund, 1944, 1959-1960, undated (Box 87, Folder 2037)
  - Wisseman, Charles L., 1968-1969 (Box 87, Folder 2038)
  - Wolff, Dorothy, 1957 (Box 87, Folder 2039)
  - Womack, C. Ray, 1957 (Box 87, Folder 2040)
  - Wong, Sam C., 1952-1954 (Box 87, Folder 2041)
  - Wood, Ian, 1946, 1951, 1966, 1971, undated (Box 87, Folder 2042)
  - Wood, W. Barry, 1940-1944, 1947, 1965, 1968-1971 (Box 87, Folder 2043)
  - Woodward, T. E., 1956-1959 (Box 87, Folder 2044)
    See also: box 84, folder 1936
  - Workman, W. G., 1952-1956 (Box 87, Folder 2045)
  - World Academy of Art and Science, 1960-1964-1968, 1973, undated (Box 87, Folder 2046-2047)
  - World Alliance of Young Men's Christian Associations, 1957 (Box 87, Folder 2048)
  - World Book Encyclopedia, 1957 (Box 87, Folder 2049)
  - World Constitution, 1961-1962 (Box 87, Folder 2050)
  - World Health Organization
    - General, 1952-1956, 1959-1963 (Box 88, Folder 2051)
    - General, 1965-1973, 1977 (Box 88, Folder 2052)
    - Expert Advisory Panel on Virus Diseases, 1950, 1956-1959, 1962, 1968-1975 (Box 88, Folder 2053)
    - Geneva meeting on viruses and cancer, 1964 (Box 88, Folder 2054)
    - Poliomyelitis Expert Committee, 1953 (Box 88, Folder 2055)
  - Wright, Joyce, 1948-1949, 1954 (Box 88, Folder 2056)
  - Wright, Peter, 1973-1975 (Box 88, Folder 2057)
  - Wu, Chao-Ten, 1957 (Box 88, Folder 2058)
  - Wyckoff, Ralph W. G., 1957 (Box 88, Folder 2059)
  - Wyeth Laboratories, 1958-1959 (Box 88, Folder 2060)
  - Wyss, Orville, 1968 (Box 88, Folder 2061)
  - Yale University, 1953-1955, 1959-1974 (Box 88, Folder 2062)
  - Year Book Publishers, Inc., 1954-1955 (Box 88, Folder 2063)
  - Yerganian, George, 1962, 1965-1968, 1978 (Box 88, Folder 2064)
  - Yoffey, J. M., 1954 (Box 88, Folder 2065)
  - Young, Nathaniel, 1974, undated (Box 88, Folder 2066)
  - Youngner, J. S., 1954-1955 (Box 88, Folder 2067)
  - Yugoslav Immunological Society, 1969-1970 (Box 88, Folder 2068)
  - Zaia, John A., undated (Box 88, Folder 2069)
  - Zamecnik, Paul, 1971 (Box 88, Folder 2070)
  - Zhdanov, V., 1960-1962, 1968-1971, undated (Box 88, Folder 2071)
  - Zinsser, Hans, 1936-1951, 1955, 1961, 1971-1972, undated (Box 88, Folder 2072)
  - Zu Rhein, Gabriele, 1965 (Box 88, Folder 2073)
  - Zygmuntowicz, Aniela S., 1961 (Box 88, Folder 2074)
  - Unidentified, 1951, 1955, 1969 (Box 88, Folder 2075)
- Writings, 1930-1972; Series II; 5.25' (13 boxes)
  This series contains two subseries, Articles and Papers and Lecture and Presentation Notes. Articles and Papers is arranged chronologically; within each year the material is arranged alphabetically by title. Undated material follows the dated material. Lecture and Presentation Notes are arranged by type of material.
  - Articles and Papers
    - 1930
      - A Type Specific Substance Distinct from the Specific Carbohydrate in Pneumococcus Type I (Box 89, Folder 1)
    - 1932
      - Dissociation of the Meningococcus Following Cultivation in Normal Rabbit's Serum (Box 89, Folder 2)
    - 1934
      - Malignant Panleucopenia of Cats: A Virus Disease (Box 89, Folder 3)
      - Studies on Pneumococcus Type III: I. Observations in vitro on Certain Differences between Strains of Pneumococcus Type III Varying in their Virulence for Rabbits (Box 89, Folder 4)
      - Studies on Pneumococcus Type III: IV. Virulence for Rabbits of S Forms of Two Strains of Pneumococcus Type III Derived from the Respective R Variants by the Method of Griffith (Box 89, Folder 5)
    - 1936
      - Preliminary Observations on a Form of the Soluble Specific Substance of Pneumococcus Type III Possessing Certain Properties Distinct from SSS III (Box 89, Folder 6)
      - Studies on Pneumococcus Type III: I. Observations in vitro on Certain Differences between Two Strains of Pneumococcus Type III Varying in their Virulence for Rabbits (Box 89, Folder 7)
      - The Uses of Vaccines and Serums (Box 89, Folder 8)
      - Variation in Susceptibility of Guinea Pigs to Reversed Passive Anphylaxis (Box 89, Folder 9)
    - 1939
      - The Virus of Herpes Simplex on the Chorioallantoic Membrane of the Developing Chick Embryo (Box 89, Folder 10)
    - 1940
      - The Combined Effect of Non-Type Specific Antipneumococcus Serum and Sodium Sulfapyridine in Mice Infected with Pneumococcus Type III (Box 89, Folder 11)
      - Etiology of Measles (Box 89, Folder 12)
      - The Prolonged Co-Existence of Vaccinia Virus in High Titre and Living Cells in Roller Tube Cultures of Chick Embryonic Tissues (Box 89, Folder 13)
      - Psittacocis (Box 89, Folder 14)
    - 1941
      - Absence of Clinical Disease in Spite of a High Incidence of Carriers of Group A Hemolytic Streptococci of a Single Type: Failure of Tyrothricin to Influence the Carrier Rate (Box 89, Folder 15)
      - The Present State of Our Knowledge of the Spirochaete and of Immunity to Syphilis (Box 89, Folder 16)
      - The Roller Tube Tissue Culture Method in the Study of Viruses (Box 89, Folder 17)
      - A Vaccine Against European Typhus Prepared by X-Ray Irradiation of the White Mouse (Box 89, Folder 18)
    - 1942
      - The Detection of Antibody by Complement-Fixation in the Sera of Man and Monkey Convalescent from Mumps (Box 89, Folder 19)
    - 1943
      - Observations on Immunity in Mumps (Box 89, Folder 20)
    - 1944
      - Chemical, Clinical and Immunological Studies on the Products of Human Plasma Fractionation (Box 89, Folder 21)
      - Observations on the Effect of Fractionation upon Virus in Plasma Together with Notes on the Thermal Inactivation at Moderate Temperatures of Certain Viruses and Bacteria Suspended in Solutions of Human Protein (Box 89, Folder 22)
    - 1945
      - Immunity in Mumps I (Box 89, Folder 23)
      - Immunity in Mumps II (Box 89, Folder 24)
      - Immunity in Mumps III (Box 89, Folder 25)
      - The Multiplication of Mumps Virus in the Amniotic Sac of the Embryonated Hen's Egg and the Agglutinative Effect of the Infected Amniotic Fluid on Fowl's Erythrocytes (Box 89, Folder 26)
    - 1946
      - Attenuation of Virulence with Retention of Antigenicity of Mumps Virus After Passage in the Embryonated Egg (Box 89, Folder 27)
      - Immunity in Mumps IV (Box 90, Folder 28)
      - Immunity in Mumps V (Box 90, Folder 29)
      - Immunity in Mumps VI (Box 90, Folder 30)
      - Mumps: Techniques of Laboratory Diagnosis, Tests for Susceptibility and Experiments on Specific Prophylaxis (Box 90, Folder 31)
    - 1947
      - An Epidemic Diarrhoel Disease of Suckling Mice: II. Inclusions in the Intestinal Epithelial Cells (Box 90, Folder 32)
      - The Immunology of Mumps (Box 90, Folder 33)
      - Immunologic Reactions Following the Intradermal Inoculation of Influenza A and B Vaccine (Box 90, Folder 34)
      - Propagation of Viruses and Rickettsiae in Tissue Cultures (Box 90, Folder 35)
      - Society of American Bacteriologists Round Table Discussion: Mumps (Box 90, Folder 36)
      - Studies on Active Immunization Against Mumps (Box 90, Folder 37)
      - Virus as Antigen with Special Reference to Mumps (Box 90, Folder 38)
    - 1948
      - The Etiology of the Diarrhea of Infancy (Box 90, Folder 39)
      - A Hemolysin Associated with the Mumps Virus (Box 90, Folder 40)
      - The Laboratory Diagnosis of Certain Viral Encephalitides (Box 90, Folder 41)
      - Mumps (Chapter 24 in Viral and Rickettsial Infections of Man ) (Box 90, Folder 42)
      - Mumps (Chapter 24 in Viral and Rickettsial Infections of Man ) (Box 90, Folder 43)
      - Mumps (Chapter 24 in Viral and Rickettsial Infections of Man ) (Box 91, Folder 44)
      - The Present State of Investigation Concerning the Etiology of Acute Non-Bacterial Infectious Diarrheas (Box 91, Folder 45)
      - The Production of Hemogglutinin by Mumps and Influenza A Viruses in Suspended Cell Tissue Cultures (Box 91, Folder 46)
      - The Propagation of Viruses and Rickettsiae in Tissue Cultures (chapter in Viral and Rickettsial Infections of Man ) (Box 91, Folder 47)
    - 1949
      - Antihemagglutinin in the Diagnosis of Infections by the Mumps Virus (Box 91, Folder 48)
      - Cultivation of the Lansing Strain of Poliomyelitis Virus in Cultures of Various Human Embryonic Tissues (Box 91, Folder 49)
      - The Cultivation of Poliomyelitis Virus in Cultures of Human Foreskin and Embryonic Tissue (Box 91, Folder 50)
      - The Differential Diagnosis of Non-Paralytic Poliomyelitis and Mumps Meningoencephalitis (Box 91, Folder 51)
      - An Evaluation of the Test for Antihemagglutinin in the Diagnosis of Infections by the Mumps Virus (Box 91, Folder 52)
      - Lansing Strain Cultivation (Box 91, Folder 53)
      - Remarks on Cellular Resistance to Mammalian Viruses (Box 91, Folder 54)
      - Viruses in the Oropharynx and Nasal Passages (Box 91, Folder 55)
    - 1950
      - Certain Aspects of Mumps Meningoencephalitis (Box 91, Folder 56)
      - Cytopathogenic Effect of Poliomyelitis Viruses in vitro on Human Embryonic Tissues (Box 91, Folder 57)
      - The Etiology of Epidemic Pleurodynia: A Study of Two Viruses Isolated from a Typical Outbreak (Box 91, Folder 58)
      - Some Aspects of Tissue Culture Techniques as Applied to the Study of Animal Viruses (Box 91, Folder 59)
      - Some Aspects of Tissue Culture Techniques as Applied to the Study of Animal Viruses (Box 91, Folder 60)
      - Some Aspects of Tissue Culture Techniques as Applied to the Study of Animal Viruses (Box 92, Folder 61)
      - Toxic Effect on the Chick Embryo of Homologous Tissue Suspensions Following Intravenous Inoculation (Box 92, Folder 62)
    - 1951
      - Antibodies in Human Gamma Globulin (Box 92, Folder 63)
      - The in vitro Effect of Poliomyelitis Virus on Various Human Cell Types (Box 92, Folder 64)
      - Isolation of Polio Virus (Box 92, Folder 65)
      - The Multiplication and Properties of Poliomyelitis Viruses in Cultures of Human Tissue (Box 92, Folder 66)
      - Studies on the Cultivation of Poliomyelitis Viruses in Tissue Cultures: II (Box 92, Folder 67)
      - Studies on the Cultivation of Poliomyelitis Viruses in Tissue Culture: V. (Box 92, Folder 68)
    - 1952
      - Alteration in Pathogenicity for Monkeys of the Brunhilde Strain of Poliomyelitis Virus Following Cultivation in Human Tissues (Box 92, Folder 69)
      - Antibodies in Human Gamma Globulin (Box 92, Folder 70)
      - Application of Tissue Culture to the Study Of Viral Diseases with Particular Reference to Poliomyelitis (Box 92, Folder 71)
      - Complement Fixation with Brunhilde and Lansing Poliomyelitis Viruses Propagated in Tissue Culture (Box 92, Folder 72)
      - Complement Fixation with the Three Types of Poliomyelitis Viruses Propagated in Tissue Culture (Box 92, Folder 73)
      - Discussion of Techniques Used in the Cultivation of Poliomyelitis Viruses in Suspended Cell Cultures (Box 92, Folder 74)
      - General Preface to Studies on the Cultivation of Poliomyelitis Viruses in Tissue Culture (Box 92, Folder 75)
      - Hypersensitivity to Viral Infections (Box 92, Folder 76)
      - Poliomyelitis Viruses Propagated in Tissue Cultures as Antigens in the Complement Fixation Test (Box 92, Folder 77)
      - Studies on the Cultivation of Poliomyelitis Viruses in Tissue Culture: I. (Box 92, Folder 78)
      - Studies on the Cultivation of Poliomyelitis Viruses in Tissue Culture: II. (Box 92, Folder 79)
    - 1953
      - Bovine Amniotic Fluid as Basis of a Medium in Roller Tube Cultures of Human Tissues for Use in the Propagation of Poliomyelitis and Other Viruses (Box 93, Folder 80)
      - Bovine Amniotic Fluid as Tissue Culture Medium in Cultivation of Poliomyelitis and Other Viruses (Box 93, Folder 81)
      - Recent Advances in Poliomyelitis (Box 93, Folder 82)
      - Some Recent Advances in the Study of Poliomyelitis (Box 93, Folder 83)
    - 1954
      - The Application of Tissue Cultures to the Preparation and Assay of Viral Antibodies (Box 93, Folder 84)
      - The Cultivation of the Poliomyelitis Viruses in Tissue Culture [Nobel Lecture] (Box 93, Folder 85)
      - Cytopathogenic Agents Isolated from Patients During an Unusual Epidemic Exanthem (Box 93, Folder 86)
      - Cytopathology of Virus Infections (Box 93, Folder 87)
      - Isolation of a Cytopathogenic Agent from an Infant with a Disease in Certain Respects Resembling Roseola Infantum (Box 93, Folder 88)